Yu-Siang Huang (黄郁翔)

• https://remyhuang.github.io • sm840816@gmail.com • Taipei, Taiwan

SHORT BIO

I'm currently a master student at National Taiwan University under the supervision of Yi-Hsuan Yang. Before that, I undertook research work at Microsoft and Academia Sinica. My research interests include music information retrieval and natural language processing for music.

EDUCATION

National Taiwan University

M.S., Computer Science

September 2018 - Present

National Tsing Hua University

B.S., Industrial Engineering; GPA: 3.91/4.3

September 2013 - June 2017

Hsinchu, Taiwan

Taipei, Taiwan

WORK EXPERIENCE

Microsoft

Software Engineering Intern at Xiaoice Science Team

March 2018 - August 2018

Beijing, China

* Advisor: Ruihua Song

* Lyrics Generation, Mondegreen Generation

Academia Sinica

June 2017 - February 2018

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Assistant at Music and Audio Computing Lab

* Advisor: Yi-Hsuan Yang

* Music Highlight Extraction, Music Content-based Retrieval (genre & emotion), AI DJ project

Tsing Hua University

July 2016 - August 2016

Beijing, China

Summer Exchange Student at Computer Science

* Advisor: Haizhou Ai

* Preliminary Examination of Computer Vision

PUBLICATION

[1] Pop Music Highlighter: Marking the Emotion Keypoints

Yu-Siang Huang, Szu-Yu Chou, Yi-Hsuan Yang

Transactions of the International Society for Music Information Retrieval, vol.1, no.1, 2018

[2] Generating Music Medleys via Playing Music Puzzle Games

Yu-Siang Huang, Szu-Yu Chou, Yi-Hsuan Yang

Proceedings of the 32nd AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, 2018

[3] Music Thumbnailing via Neural Attention Modeling of Music Emotion

Yu-Siang Huang, Szu-Yu Chou, Yi-Hsuan Yang

Asia-Pacific Signal and Information Processing Association Annual Summit and Conference, 2017